Wilson Souza de Medeiros Junior

+351 931-919-391

wilsonmdrs@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/wilson-medeiros-381711109 Portugal

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As a Software Engineer with extensive experience in developing web applications, I am a highly motivated and adaptable team player with strong technical expertise. My ability to apply theoretical concepts to practical situations, attention to detail, and positive attitude towards work make me an excellent candidate for any challenging opportunity.

WORK EXPERIENCE

React Native Developer

Jun 2023 - Present

Mobiweb · Portugal

- Developed design interfaces based on design patterns.
- Spearheading the architecture design and development of React Native mobile applications.
- Conducting comprehensive code reviews to ensure adherence to best practices and coding standards
- Worked on bug fixes providing measures to prevent future performance issues.
- Developed layout systems, responsive design, accessible and user-friendly interfaces.

Frontend Developer

Jul 2022 - Mar 2023

Red IT · Portugal

- Developed design interfaces based on design patterns.
- Worked on a DevOps environment.
- Developed documentation about Testing React Components with Jest and provided training sessions in order to help team members to apply unit test on components.
- Provided assistance for Junior Frontend Developers.
- Worked on bug fixes providing measures to prevent future performance issues.

Software Engineer

Oct 2019 - Mar 2022

Exact Code Sistemas · Brazil

- Planned, developed, tested, deployed, and maintained web applications with React and mobile applications with React Native.
- Developed RESTful API with Node.JS and Python
- Provided effective troubleshooting and remediation for web applications.
- Planned and developed knowledge bases for virtual assistants.

Software Developer Freelancer Mar 2017 – Oct 2019

Exact Code Sistemas · Brazil

- Developed Web and Mobile Application with React and React Native.
- Developed RESTful API with Node.JS and Python.
- Learned and Applied Theorical computing concepts on AI projects.
- Learned web development principles and tools for better web applications.

EDUCATION

Computer Science, Bachelor

Mar 2012 – Jun 2022

Brazil

SKILLS

- Javascript Advanced
- Typescript Advanced
- React JS Advanced
- React Native Advanced
- Python. intermediate
- HTML5 advanced
- CSS3 advanced
- Styled Components Advanced
- SASS Advanced
- Node JS Intermediate
- Adobe XD advanced
- FIGMA Advanced
- Jest Advanced
- React Query Intermediate
- Tailwind Intermediate
- Jest Advanced
- React Testing Library Advanced
- Storybook Advanced

LANGUAGES

- Full proficiency in Portuguese (native language).
- Full professional proficiency in English.